Ernestine Gilbreth Carey Papers, 1915-2005
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. WRITINGS
  - Books (Box 45)
    - Giddy Moment 1958 (Box 50)
      - Publicity, 1958-62 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Research materials, 1947-57 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Book jacket and imprint, 1958 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Early table of contents, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Manuscript drafts (2), undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Notes on index cards, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Jumping Jupiter 1952 (Box 51)
      - Book summary, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Book review, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Research material, undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Fan mail, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Notes, 1951 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Character sketches and plot developments, undated, c.1951 (Box 52, Folder 6-6c)
      - Manuscript drafts, n.d., c.1951-52 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - "Razzle Dazzle," aka "A Wonderful Life Off and Away" (unpublished, circa 1970s) (Box 53-55)
      - Drafts, fragments, and notes (Box 53-55)
    - Rings Around Us 1956 (Box 53-55)
      - Book synopsis, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - Publicity, 1959 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Book jacket and imprint, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 1962-76 (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - Typescript (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Munsey Park Association brochure (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Published books-hardcover editions (Box 55)
      - Frank B. Gilbreth, Jr. and Ernestine Gilbreth Carey, Belles on Their Toes (Garden City, NY: International Collector's Library, 1950) (Box 55)
      - Frank B. Gilbreth, Jr. and Ernestine Gilbreth Carey, Cheaper by the Dozen (Garden City, NY: International Collector's Library, 1950) (Box 55)
      - Ernestine Gilbreth Carey, Rings Around Us (Boston: Little,Brown & Co., 1956) (Box 55)
      - Frank B. Gilbreth, Jr., Ancestors of the Dozen (Columbia, SC:The R.L. Bryan Company, 1994) (Box 55)
    - Published books-paperback editions (Box 56)
      - Frank B. Gilbreth, Jr. and Ernestine Gilbreth Carey, Belles on Their Toes (New York: Bantam Books, 1984) [inscribed by EGC To Sophia Smith Collection Director Susan Grigg, 8/11/88] (Box 56)
      - Frank B. Gilbreth, Jr. and Ernestine Gilbreth Carey, Cheaper by the Dozen [Japanese edition, 1949] (Box 56)
      - Frank B. Gilbreth, Jr. and Ernestine Gilbreth Carey, Cheaper by the Dozen (New York: Bantam Books, 1976). (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Frank B. Gilbreth, Jr. and Ernestine Gilbreth Carey, Cheaper by the Dozen (New York: Perennial Classics, 2002). (Box 56)
  - Diaries (Box 56)
    - 1917 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - 1948-54 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - 1955-58 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - 1960-65 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - 1966-69, diary 1917, used for Cheaper by the Dozen (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - 1970-77 (bound notebook) (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - 1970-71 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - 1974 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - 1975 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - 1983-85 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - 1985 (bound notebook) (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - 1986-87 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - 1988-89 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - 1990 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - 1991-94 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - 1995-2001 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - 2002-2003 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Diary, undated (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Diary fragments (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Taped diary transcript (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Drafts, fragments, and notes (Box 57)
    - "A Mother's Place," 1943-1944 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - "A Very Good Buy," 1927 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Arizona, general (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Arizona, chapter 18 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Authors Guild, 1960s-2000s (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Barney, Anne Gilbreth (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - Barnum, Gerry (Box 57, Folder 18)
    - Book review, newspaper clippings, 1960s-80s (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography, 1975-85 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Biography writing (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Book planning 1950s-80s (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - California trip, 1955 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Carey, Charles Everett, Jr. (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Christmas (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - College and summers (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Copyright, 1950s-80s (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Cousin Adelaide, undated (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Craft, 1950-51 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Craft, 1950s-70s (Box 58, Folder 12-13)
    - Essential craft 1967 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Craft 1960s (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Craft, Truman biography, David McCullough (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Craft, cartoon, undated (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Craft, article: Reader's Digest, undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Creativity, 1950s-70s (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Creativity, notes: Huxley and genius, undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Cross, Aunt Anne Gilbreth, 1920s-70s (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - "Customers Come First," 1990s (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Daughters-mothers, undated (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - "The Elephant Story" (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Eye surgery/1960s-70s (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Family Log, excerpts (1923-) (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Fan mail project (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Fiction writing for adults/fiction craft 1960s-70s (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Films, undated (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - "For the Birds," undated (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - "Frogs Strictly Forbidden" (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Gambling, Cal-Neva (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Gifts from: diary notes, 1978, 1994 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Gilbreth friends, undated (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - Gilbreth kin, undated (Box 59, Folder 22)
    - Gilbreth, Frank, 1973-94 (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - Gilbreth, Lillian (Box 59)
      - General (Box 59, Folder 24)
      - Autobiography, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 25)
      - Stamp celebration, 1984 (Box 59, Folder 26)
    - Gilbreth, Grandma Martha, undated (Box 59, Folder 27)
    - "Holiday Guest," 1973 (Box 59, Folder 28)
    - "The Hurricane," 1954 (Box 59, Folder 29)
    - Informal dress (Box 59, Folder 30)
    - "Jack's Sunstroke," 1970 (Box 59, Folder 31)
    - Jackson, Phyllis (Box 59, Folder 32)
    - Juvenile 1950s-70s (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
    - Juvenile 1970s-90s, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 3-5)
    - Juvenile manuscripts, 1994-95 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Juvenile poems (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Juvenile newspaper articles, 1970s-80s (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Lecturing, 1953, 1990 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Letter excerpts, 1950 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Library room notes 1961 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - "Minnie Guenter, Arizona Mother of the Year, 1967" (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Moller kin, 1978 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Motion-and-Time-Saving course, Macy's, undated (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - "Mum's the Word," 1970s, various drafts (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Nantucket, early summers, Montclair, 1977, undated (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Netherwood house; Plainfield, NJ (some Providence house included) (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - Notes on authors (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - "Odds," 1970s-90s (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Parties (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Penn. State (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Poetry (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Porter, David, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Prize winners, 1970s (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Providence house (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Purdue University, 1970s-80s (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Rainbow Valley land, 1980s (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Reading for proposal, 1970s-90s (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - "Recollections," undated (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Recommended collections of short stories, 1970s (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - "Speak Softly Please," 1960s-80s (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Summer, 1960s (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - Teeny Bunk Hen Company, n..d. (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - "Telephone," 1950s (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - "Thanks to Terry," 1954 (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - "To a Star," poem, undated (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - Travel (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - "Up Above the World So High," 1970s-2000s (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - "Veteran's Hospital," 1953 (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - "Who Needs Women's Lib?" 1970 (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - "Why be a Woman?" 1966 (Box 61, Folder 24)
    - Winnie, dog (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Writers, undated (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Writing, current, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - Drafts, fragments, and notes, untitled (Box 62, Folder 1-3)
    - Post publication thoughts, Cheaper by the Dozen (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Notes, writings by others: writing process (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Diary entry notes, 1960s (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Playwriting craft: notes (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Notebooks (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Reference notes (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Background materials (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Article ideas (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Writings, undated (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - "Lo Project: background: The Age" (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - Diary notes, Childhood and Providence, R.I. years (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - Diary notes, 1959 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Notes, autobiographical piece (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Fragments, diary notes, Manhasset, New York, 1948 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 63)
    - Book reviews (Box 63)
      - L. Homer, Golden Age of Opera (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - R. Leckie, Lord What A Family (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Books about Children by Various Authors (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Frank B. Gilbreth, Jr., Time Out for Happiness (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Royalty sheets, domestic sales 1956-59 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Royalty sheets, assorted foreign sales (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Contracts and payments (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Drafts of article written 1949-50 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Notes for diary, summer of 1949 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Diary file, 1969 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Notes for autobiography (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Draft manuscript, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Drafts, ideas, notes, etc. (Box 63, Folder 14)
- SERIES IV. SPEECHES AND APPEARANCES
  - Correspondence, 1949-66 (Box 64)
  - Financial, 1960, undated (Box 64)
  - Itineraries, 1954-61 (Box 64)
  - Publicity, 1949-91 (Box 64)
  - Lectures, 1950-66 (Box 64)
  - Carey v. Peat, 1950-57 (Box 64)
  - "Odds and Ends," 1940s-70s (Box 64)
  - Lecture note cards, undated (Box 64)
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES
  - Cartoons, 1960s-70s, n.d. (Box 65)
  - Censorship and right to read, 1970s (Box 65)
  - Family histories/genealogy (Box 65)
  - Family histories/genealogy (Box 66)
  - Inventions, patents, and business ideas, 1960s-70s (Box 66)
  - Macy's, 1939-96 (Box 66)
  - Smith College, 1927-2007 (Box 66)
    - Papers and examinations, 1927-29 (Box 66)
    - Class of 1929 Reunions, 1954-69 (Box 66)
    - Trustee materials, 1969-73 (Box 66)
    - Correspondence (various offices), 1962-2007 (Box 67)
  - Travel (Box 67)
    - Diaries (Box 67)
    - Grand European Tour, 1929 (Box 68)
    - Japan and Far East, 1973 (Box 68)
    - Paris, Spain, Portugal, and North Africa, 1974 (Box 68)
    - Great Britain, 1976 (Box 68)
    - California, 1978 and 1979 (Box 68)
    - London, 1982 (Box 68)
    - Montclair, New Jersey, 1985 (Box 68)
    - Germany, 1988 (Box 68)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970s-2001 (Box 68)
    - Notebooks (Box 68)
    - Japan and Far East, 1973 (Box 68)
    - Egypt, 1975 (Box 68)
    - Purdue trip, 1976 (Box 68)
    - England, 1977 (Box 68)
    - Germany, 1988 (Box 68)
    - Itineraries, 1959-90 (Box 68)
    - Notes, 1970s (Box 68)
    - Montreal Expo, 1967 (Box 68)
    - European trip, 1972 (Box 68)
    - Spain, Portugal, and North Africa, 1974 (Box 68)
    - California, 1975 (Box 68)
    - Egypt, 1975 (Box 68)
    - California, 1977 (Box 68)
    - Mediterranean, 1977 (Box 68)
    - Alpine, 1980 (Box 68)
    - Viking tour, 1984 (Box 68)
    - Germany, 1980s (Box 68)
    - Travel expenses, 1987-88 (Box 68)
  - Women in Engineering (Box 68)
    - General, 1966-94 (Box 68)
    - Society of Women Engineers, 1969-70 (Box 68)
  - Women's Liberation, 1969-70 (Box 68)
- SERIES VI. LILLIAN MOLLER GILBRETH AND FRANK BUNKER GILBRETH, SR.
  - Research notes, correspondence and drafts (Box 69-71)
- SERIES VII. PHOTOGRAPHS AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS
  - Photographs (Box 72-73)
  - Audiovisual materials (Box 74-75)
- SERIES VIII. MEMORABILIA
  - Scrapbooks (Box 76-77)
  - Memorabilia (Box 78-79)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Scrapbooks (Box 80-84)
  - Cheaper By the Dozen illustrated fan mail from children, 1950 (Box 85)
  - Institute of Industrial Engineers 50th Anniversary poster featuring Lillian and Frank Gilbreth, 1998 (Map-case Flat file dwr 21)